Daz: Hey, hey!
Ben Pfaff: Hello!
Joe Beda: Hello, hello!
Daz: Hello, hello. How is everyone doing?
Ben Pfaff: I'm doing good
Daz: Desk is a bit of a mess, so my...
Joe Beda: Yeah, my office started out clean when we moved into this house, and it's slowly deteriorating, and I need to take another pass at it.
Ben Pfaff: I'm beginning to remember why owning a house is a pain sometimes.
Joe Beda: This is my take is that, like, it doesn't matter what house it is. It's like, you're like, oh, the new house will be better. No, you're just trading old problems for new problems. There is no, like...
Ben Pfaff: Well, the current problem is that the irrigation system stopped working in some of the zones.
Joe Beda: Well, you just need to get a shovel and fix it. I mean, like...
Ben Pfaff: Well, so there were there were people like dragging pipes by some of them a couple weeks ago because the sewer lateral need to be replaced. So I suspect that something got bumped or screwed up or whatever. And I don't know how any of it works because I didn't put it in. So I'm going to have to go find out.
Joe Beda: Yeah, that's the other thing with the house. There's always spelunking, right?
Ben Pfaff: Well, there's actually a very nice map and list of what's supposed to be where, but, I mean, it doesn't help enough. It just means that I know what those zones' numbers should be.
Joe Beda: Well, like the previous house, I moved in and there was, like, Cat 5 run to a bunch of places, but it was used as telephone wire, and so then it was put into sort of punch-down blocks that was telephone. Nothing was labeled in terms of which cable went where, and then all the jacks were RJ11 instead of RJ45, so, like...
Joe Beda: I had to get like a tone generator and go through and like map those things out and then I had this handwritten list of like well and then I got these new like punch down little punch down things and then I had a handwritten list of like well you know number one on this block is blah blah blah and I left that for the new owner I'm like you can thank me later
Ben Pfaff: Thank you for watching!
Daz: Subtitles by the Amara.org community
Joe Beda: Hey, how's it going, man?
Daz: Hey, Christophers.
Kostadis Roussos: Putting on my headphones.
Joe Beda: Where are you at? You are in a hotel room.
Kostadis Roussos: I'll tell you in a sec. Give me a sec.
Joe Beda: That is definitely hotel room-esque.
Ben Pfaff: Okay, did that help? Let's see.
Joe Beda: Looks like a nice hotel room though.
Ben Pfaff: Nope. All right. Well, thanks, Chad.
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on. I got the right devices.
Ben Pfaff: I'm saying you said a spider. Slider. It slides from side to side, not spider.
Joe Beda: Is Gabe joining us today? Do you know?
Daz: No, he said he was off for the next two weeks, I think, last time.
Joe Beda: Wow. Bummer.
Ben Pfaff: That's all. Jamie has a lot more space in this place, and I guess it's making her less excited about sitting and watching me play D&D.
Joe Beda: Is that her Monday entertainment anymore?
Ben Pfaff: I guess not like there's a there there's a a TV here that isn't directly back of where I'm sitting
Kostadis Roussos: So yes, I'm in a hotel room in LA. My son is doing an internship at a company. I have a buddy of mine.
Joe Beda: And you're visiting and saying hi?
Kostadis Roussos: No, I'm taking care of him. He's 16 years old. I can't have him staying alone in the way.
Joe Beda: Oh, interesting. So Nora's doing an internship. She's 17, but she's doing it remote because the company doesn't have any offices.
Kostadis Roussos: I see.
Joe Beda: So I have discussions with her. I'm like, you're playing guitar. They're paying you for this time. Are there things that you could be doing? She's like, well, I'm blocked on something and waiting for somebody to reply. I'm like, well, in the real world, you have multiple, you know, balls in the air that you juggle. And when you get blocked on one thing, you find something else to be useful for. And like, she did not appreciate my feedback. So, you know.
Kostadis Roussos: Didn't appreciate your feedback.
Joe Beda: No, it turns out that a lot of times the kids don't appreciate my sage advice. I don't understand it.
Ben Pfaff: Well, you know, I've got days where I just can't deal and I spend some of my downtime doing things that aren't necessarily advancing stockholder value.
Joe Beda: Yeah, I mean, but you guys, like, there's a balance there. And I just don't, I want her to be aware of like, hey, like, you know, don't like fall into the trap of like, sooner or later, you know, over time, you spend more and more time goofing off. And it's, I mean, that's one of the dangers of working remote, right, is that it's easy to fall into that sort of goofing off trap.
Ben Pfaff: That is true.
Kostadis Roussos: Especially for junior engineers who don't have a good work ethic.
Joe Beda: There's still, I would say there's still
Kostadis Roussos: You're still developing?
Joe Beda: Developing their habits, is what I would say.
Kostadis Roussos: You know, actually, what I say is, when I tell my new MTS1s, for some reason they don't let me speak to them anymore after I said this.
Ben Pfaff: All my bad habits, sir.
Kostadis Roussos: As you can see, this is the end of the video. Thank you for watching.
Ben Pfaff: I'm going to take a break now.
Kostadis Roussos: I tell them, step zero, oh, step zero, you have to prove to me you know how to work. They look at me funny, you know, like show up to work every day. Apparently, apparently that is considered poor form and not the kind of things that is appropriate to be said to new hires. Straight out of school.
Joe Beda: Grumpy old man, Kastatis.
Kostadis Roussos: So by consensus, I don't meet the MTS1s. I only meet them when they're MTS2s. That way I don't terrify them. That way there's not meetings with HR and discussions and things like that.
Joe Beda: All right, are we just going to play?
Kostadis Roussos: So, yeah, Gabe's out. Oh no, we can play.
Ben Pfaff: So I've been bad here and I haven't done my homework on what we're doing.
Kostadis Roussos: You rat bastard. All right. Yeah. So that's, you know, I figured as much, so I've prepared. I'm not even sure.
Ben Pfaff: I wonder how many sessions we've had in between.
Kostadis Roussos: Tchoo!
Ben Pfaff: Two.
Kostadis Roussos: So, a one and a half.
Joe Beda: I think I was at the last one, but I'm not sure.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, so here's what happened. You guys all managed to secure, I mean, I have a summary if you want it, I can share it with you.
Ben Pfaff: I like hearing the words, if you're willing.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, no, no, I'm absolutely willing to do that. I'm just like, the reason I said that was to give me a moment to go pull it up.
Ben Pfaff: Oh, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: It was more of a, give me a sec. So, okay, so here's what happened. All right.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, okay, so you secured Alchris' confession. You had physical evidence, and then you started to debate your own, um, your own, you started to, uh, you started to debate what to happen. Dawnbringer, of course, at that point in time, decided this was an opportune time to discuss that the Promises therapy sessions with Scandal Keeps Call, as the lyrics said, never materialize.
Kostadis Roussos: And Thorin was very sympathetic and understanding and said, I know, this is why we came here after all. Finally, after some deliberation, the group settled on a patient strategy, hand the credit to Kalan Stormbranch, let him save face after his humiliating dismissal, and collect a reward. You guys thought with all the evidence you had, you'd be able to go in and march in and everybody would bow before you.
Kostadis Roussos: However, Kalan pointed out that to temper your expectations, he argued with academic precision that a single confession, however dramatic, was not enough to bring Bookworm to justice under the rigorous standards of his own investigative framework. He shoved his paper, the thrice-fold proof, into their faces and insisted that the clever play was patience.
Kostadis Roussos: With the naming ceremony approaching, the stench of suspicion alone would be enough to deny Bookworm the position of first keeper, and the new head of the avowed would be far more motivated to see her undone. The party agreed, and then Thorin added a cunning wrinkle of his own. They would use the reward to acquire whatever resource or tome that might definitively prove Bookworm's role as an accomplice after the fact, striking when she least suspected.
Kostadis Roussos: The confrontation in Bookworm's office was a master class in controlled tension. She received you with regal composure, pouring tea and gesturing for you to sit, an offer you declined with varying degrees of suspension. Xalter, unwilling to be rude, but equally unwilling to trust the cup, quietly directed Glabigold to absorb the three through his arm. The faint singe of acid, the only sign anything unusual had occurred.
Kostadis Roussos: When Kalan laid out the evidence against Alcris, the stolen poison, the book, the confession, the workworm's composure cracked, and she appeared heartbroken. But Daz, watching her carefully, noticed something the others missed. Beneath the grief, she looked curiously relieved. We chose to withhold what they knew about the potential accomplices, hinting only that the investigation was not yet complete, and that others may have been involved.
Kostadis Roussos: Bookworm performed outrage beautifully, declaring it unthinkable that anyone would have aspired in the death of her beloved Janussi. Kalan was reinstated to his position, his methodology vindicated at last, and Brinkrum graciously announced that the party would be given a full opportunity to speak before the naming ceremony. She then arranged for them to be escorted to Deneir's sanctum, framing it as protection.
Kostadis Roussos: Though Daz sensed it was equally about keeping them from poking their noses any further into Candlekeep's affairs. A brief detour to Alcrist's room yielded little of consequence. The safe contained gold, a pair of potions, and, as Joe put it, Jimmy Hoffa's chest.
Kostadis Roussos: A gold coin with a red herring engraved upon it, a fitting symbol for an investigation full of misdirection. The avowed declared that the contents unremarkable and moved to close the matter. Butts out there never want to miss an opportunity, used Glabagool to quietly pocket the potion of flying, while everyone else was distracted. No one noticed a thing.
Kostadis Roussos: The peace shattered without warning. The evening in Deneir's sanctum passed quietly at first. Food was brought in, which the party eyed with deep suspicion, allowing Fembris to eat first before touching anything themselves.
Kostadis Roussos: Dawnbringer was finally called upon to cure Daryl of his lingering affliction, and the man was so overcrumbed with gratitude that he launched an enthusiastic monologue about his plans to make sentient magical swords, an area of serious academic study, going on at considerable length about the semiotics of the subject, while Dawnbringer absorbed every word with evident delight.
Kostadis Roussos: Daryl then attempted to leave the room, only to find it was locked. The peace shattered without warning. Three helmed-towering animated suits of plate armor with cold, glowing eyes
Ben Pfaff: Well, that's a classic.
Kostadis Roussos: Smashed through the windows and burst through the door of the sanctum, sending the room into chaos. The construct moved with terrifying purpose, ignoring most of the party and converging almost entirely on Daz. It was only mid-battle, as the horrors relentlessly bypassed every other target to reach them, that Raz realized with a chill what they were after. The mysterious key carried, the one that had appeared completely inert to magical detection.
Kostadis Roussos: He passed it to Grygum and threw himself clear as his companion surged into the fight. The battle was fierce and disorienting. Saltyr drove his fist into the animated armor while Glabagool fused to his arm unleashed torrents of corrosive acid that began dissolving the construct's plating.
Kostadis Roussos: Grygum radiated a burst of holy light that seared two horrors within reach, while Daz hurled volleys of magical fire and force into the fray. Thorin struck with Dawnbringer, imposing disadvantage on one horror's next attack with a sapping blow before cutting it down entirely. One by one, the constructs collapsed into heats of rust and broken metal. When the last one fell, the party stood in the wreckage of the sanctum, breathing hard and deeply unsettled.
Kostadis Roussos: Because the horrors had been mindless, incapable of thought or speech, and yet somehow had known exactly who was holding a key that no spell in Candidate keep should have been able to detect. The session ended there, with the party out of time, and the mystery of the assassin's lawledge left open.
Kostadis Roussos: What the summary did not capture is that you suspected the one person you knew who had seen the drop of the key from Grygum to Daz was Fembris.
Ben Pfaff: From Daz, too?
Kostadis Roussos: Grygumite, you had originally, Kalan had given you the key.
Daz: Right.
Kostadis Roussos: Then you had given Daz the key.
Ben Pfaff: Oh, I forgot that part. Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, that happened while you were out.
Ben Pfaff: Ah, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, when you went to give your talk, you handed the key to Daz, said, I don't remember what I, I don't remember what I came up with, but since you weren't going to be around, I needed to hand it to somebody who was going to be around. So Daz had the key, Daz had the key, but Fembris apparently was still around when you handed the key and he noticed.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, so, so, all right, so there's three dead things. Daryl is, of course, like, banging at the door, let us out, let us out! Then he notices the door is open and is thinking, he's about to, he's about to try to flee, right, the door's open because the creature smashed through it.
Kostadis Roussos: And Daz, but just as he's about to run, he realizes that the only four people who seem to not want it dead are in this room. And so he looks at the four of you and asks, what do we do next, gentlemen?
Ben Pfaff: So we now suspect Ephembris?
Kostadis Roussos: Well, so here's what you know. You know that Alcrist killed Genussi, right? You know, but can't prove that Brookworm covered it up, right? You know that Alé Ivanmoor was involved, but you can't prove that.
Kostadis Roussos: Right? And you also know that a bunch of automaton came through the windows and the door to seize a key that appears to not be magical. And you have an avowed sitting here.
Daz: Hmm.
Joe Beda: I'm still, I'm having a hard time remembering who was who.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, so, um...
Joe Beda: Did you produce a doc like before, or?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, the doc click before has everything. Yes, it does have. I didn't produce, I didn't update it, unfortunately. It's okay, it's okay.
Joe Beda: But it does have, like, okay, we can see who's who, because, sorry, I'm trying to, like, it's been a while.
Kostadis Roussos: And I'm the type of person I-
Joe Beda: I read a book and I'm like, I read a name and then over time I'm like, oh yeah, that dude. And then I forget the name and I'll read the whole book and you'll ask me later like, oh, what was the name of that character that did X, Y, and Z? And I'm like, I have no fucking clue, right?
Kostadis Roussos: You don't feel bad, I mean, it's like this.
Joe Beda: It's funny because I'm like, everybody's like, oh, you remember so-and-so from this? I'm like, yep, nope, nope. You mean the dude that did blah, blah, blah? I'm like, yeah, I remember that, dude.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, hold on. I'll get you the last summary.
Joe Beda: So we think that, so...
Kostadis Roussos: Right. The most important thing, though, is that in the middle of Candlekeep, which is supposed to be one of the most fortified places in the known, in the known world, you just got attacked by three Helmed Aurors who are after a key, a key that, you know, is supposedly the key for the High Tower, which supposedly contains all sorts of magical artifacts of undoubted evil and good.
Ben Pfaff: Um, was there something about how you actually need multiple keys? Or am I just imagining that?
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, so there were, yeah, so the other, there were two keys, right? You know that Kalan had one key, and you know that Genussi had the other. Right? But you also know that Genussi's key was missing from his throat.
Ben Pfaff: Okay, so...
Kostadis Roussos: The locket was missing.
Ben Pfaff: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: You do know that between the time he was murdered and sometime later, two people visited his room, right? You know that...
Kostadis Roussos: And so, and you know that Bookworm visited his room. And you know that she knew about the key. And you also knew that Alcrist didn't want the key. He wanted Genussi dead.
Joe Beda: All right, so our theory here, then, is that Fembris reported the sort of transfer of the key to Bookworm, and Bookworm's trying to recover it because it might give them some sort of advantage in terms of being elected to be the Grand Poobah.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, that's one theory.
Joe Beda: Okay, um, I think we lean on Fembris.
Kostadis Roussos: Leon Fabros
Joe Beda: What do you guys think?
Kostadis Roussos: Thanks for watching!
Ben Pfaff: Best I've got, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on, let me just do something here.
Joe Beda: Because I'm not sure that Fembris is like a ringleader.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, I just dropped the murder investigation notes into the, all right, into the, all right.
Ben Pfaff: Oh yeah, looking at the notes would help a lot, gotta...
Kostadis Roussos: Yep.
Joe Beda: Oh, okay, there's... Okay, so part five, okay.
Daz: Well, I like this.
Kostadis Roussos: Why can't I produce more of these going forward? They're actually quite easy to produce. The very last thing is...
Daz: Oh, yeah, we have the third-story apartment landing. We haven't checked that out yet.
Kostadis Roussos: No, you did. You did check it out. That's where you found the note that Janussi thought that Kalan Strongbranch's thesis was all hooey.
Daz: Oh, that's right, that's right. Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: You found it.
Daz: I was in the wrong part.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, yeah, yeah. So Kalan Strongbranch. Yeah, so what you also discovered is that everybody loved Genussi. I mean, literally everybody. Even though he was about to fire them all. Like nobody was going to be...
Joe Beda: The fact that they were not a fan.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, no, in fact, they're all talking about how just sad and tragic his death is. By the way, Ben, you weren't there for this, but Kalan Strongbranch was confronted with the opportunity of putting a criminal in prison or having his academic theories of crime being validated, chose, of course, the obvious.
Kostadis Roussos: Easy choice.
Ben Pfaff: Easy choice.
Kostadis Roussos: A research paper program that's validated? That's priceless.
Ben Pfaff: Nobody's willing to give up their legacy like that.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah!
Ben Pfaff: And when the alternative is just going to prison.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, okay, all right, so, okay, so while you're, okay, well, tell me when you guys are done reading so I can.
Ben Pfaff: So there's a whole bunch of directions we could go here from the list of what's still open.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, but there's one important detail that kind of is scratching at you. You detected magic on this key a while ago, and it came out empty. Supposedly, this is some magical key.
Ben Pfaff: You mean we tried to detect magic and it didn't come out as magical?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Ben Pfaff: Makes me wonder if it's actually the right key.
Kostadis Roussos: Right, and just as you say that, you do remember what, um, Kalan said, which was, I think, Erg, yes, all right, just as you're thinking, just as that, uh, just as you say that,
Kostadis Roussos: They just said, you remember what he told you, Grygum, when he gave it to you. I have given it now to someone who is not me.
Ben Pfaff: Someone who is not me. Yeah, that's a weird phrasing.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Ben Pfaff: And I guess it could be sort of a hot potato kind of thing. You know, bad things are coming to whoever is holding the key when something happens.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, so what you do know is that the key has the, that somebody has a stone that could summon the key off of a dead body. You're also, he's also would be worried that somebody would kill him and steal the key.
Ben Pfaff: there's a lot that doesn't add up right um like why it's possible that it is the key but we didn't
Kostadis Roussos: You have Daryl. You could ask him whether it's the key.
Ben Pfaff: Okay, yeah, I show it to Daryl and say, you know, does this look like the key? Does anything look odd about it? The key to the tower?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, do you tell him that, well, he goes, oh, yes, well, that definitely, I mean, do you tell him that it wasn't magical, or do you just show him the key?
Ben Pfaff: Well, I start out by saying, does this look like the right key?
Kostadis Roussos: He looks at it pensively. He says, well, I'm not a locksmith, so I couldn't tell you for sure.
Ben Pfaff: Okay, so, uh, but I was given to understand that these keys were supposed to be magical and, you know, we tried
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, yes, absolutely. Yes, they're completely magical. They're the two keys that are necessary to open the Hightower. They're not some lowly, cheap-ass keys that you acquire at a locksmith. Why?
Ben Pfaff: But this key is not magical. Go ahead and examine it. Try to detect magic on it. We did not succeed.
Kostadis Roussos: He looks at it, he looks at it, he pulls out his old trusty scroll of detect magic, because, you know, if your candle keeps age, you have one of those in your pocket at all time, right? He starts reading the scroll, and, you know, your sword starts to, your armor starts to blink, bookworm is even brighter than usual.
Ben Pfaff: Oh, is this how Detect Magic works? Everything goes...
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, so it starts to glow, right? But the key, the key is stubbornly not glowing.
Ben Pfaff: I mean, it's possible someone put a charm of undetectable magic on it, but...
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, he's like going, this is not the key. This is not the key.
Daz: And it's just as that happens.
Kostadis Roussos: All of a sudden, you hear a watcher's bell starts tolling wrong. Not the hour, an alarm pattern. It's impersonal, institutional. Institutional. It's as if the keep itself is reacting to something.
Joe Beda: What does that mean?
Ben Pfaff: Anybody needs to change the battery?
Kostadis Roussos: Did it happen?
Joe Beda: Happening randomly, like, about every 90 seconds.
Kostadis Roussos: no no no no no no no um so you you someone um someone rushes in bookworm is dead
Daz: Who? Bookworm?
Kostadis Roussos: Bookworm is dead.
Daz: Huh.
Kostadis Roussos: One of the avowed GOATs, he says, do you want to ask him anything or like?
Daz: Yeah, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: I have this
Daz: How did it happen?
Ben Pfaff: Who killed him?
Kostadis Roussos: Her, first of all. Oh, okay.
Ben Pfaff: Who killed her?
Kostadis Roussos: He goes, uh, well, she had her throat torn. Like, it was torn apart.
Ben Pfaff: Does she still have her heart?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, her heart, yes, her heart was in perfectly fine condi- well, it was not beating, but it was, I mean, there's like, this is an awkward moment as this person in hysterics right now, because this is Candlekeep! These crimes don't happen in Candlekeep!
Joe Beda: Well, reality disagrees.
Ben Pfaff: I feel like we've done a poor job of serving and protecting here.
Kostadis Roussos: Do you want to go check out what's happening, what's going on?
Daz: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, uh, Fembris, uh, Fembris...
Joe Beda: You and I gotta talk to a kid real quick.
Kostadis Roussos: Fembris and Daryl rush all the way to her office, and she is like, I mean, it's a pretty gruesome mess. And it's obvious whoever did this knew what he was doing, because she is an 18th level magic user.
Ben Pfaff: Yeah, but not necessarily one who's very suspicious.
Kostadis Roussos: Right, or confident, you know, the safety of her tower, right?
Ben Pfaff: I mean, she's an academic, they don't usually, they're usually
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, instead of Time Stop and Wish, he probably has some, like, find reference to missing paper 9th level spells.
Ben Pfaff: Yeah, create citation.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, create citation. Validate citation, right? That's what she probably, identify false citations, right? Her throat is torn.
Ben Pfaff: That's a lot of blood.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, you do see a half-finished note on her desk.
Ben Pfaff: Oh, like a handwritten note?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Ben Pfaff: I definitely want to read it.
Kostadis Roussos: Um, he is using the beast to dot, dot, dot, um, you know, dead.
Ben Pfaff: The Beast
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Ben Pfaff: I turn to, I don't know, Daryl, whoever is there, and ask if they know what the beast is.
Kostadis Roussos: Daryl says, I have no idea what the beast is. Daz, roll an arcana check.
Daz: Okay, Arcana check, here it comes. I got... Are you fucking kidding me?
Kostadis Roussos: Did you get a one? You got a one! Somebody wanna help him?
Ben Pfaff: I would be delighted to...
Kostadis Roussos: All right, let's do it.
Daz: With some help, I got a 26.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so, uh, right, so
Ben Pfaff: Much better.
Kostadis Roussos: That is much better. Your headaches feel off, as if the pressure of the wards that protect Candlekeep aren't quite right. Something seems broken.
Daz: Oh, like somebody hacked the firewall and opened another port?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Joe Beda: And they snuck in some, like, you know, animated armor to attack us through that thing, or, you know?
Daz: Thank you.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes?
Joe Beda: Who knows?
Kostadis Roussos: Who knows?
Ben Pfaff: Feeling awfully sad here. People keep dying and we haven't been able to do anything about it.
Daz: Yeah, we gotta figure this out. So, if people are dying and something's been, can I, can I tell, is there anything that I know how to do to figure out what's wrong with the protection?
Joe Beda: Let's just be clear. We were hired to solve one murder. This is really not ours to solve.
Daz: Hmm
Kostadis Roussos: You, you, uh...
Daz: Thank you for watching, and I'll see you in the next video!
Ben Pfaff: You don't think solving this will lead us to the...
Joe Beda: I mean, they're probably related, just be clear, but you know, I think, you know, now's the time to renegotiate our fees, but it's not clear who we renegotiate.
Kostadis Roussos: Good trip, Whit!
Ben Pfaff: You're saying it could be...
Kostadis Roussos: Completely a coincidence. Kalan might be the right person, Oren.
Joe Beda: Alright, let's not get distracted. We can negotiate after the fact. When we have no leverage.
Kostadis Roussos: Right. Okay. So, um, so Fembris is kind of like in horror. Like, he's like completely paralyzed in fear. Daryl is like, like, standing really next to Thorin, right? He wants to be as close to Dawnbringer as possible.
Joe Beda: I mean, I'm with them, but yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: It's kind of getting a little bit awkward for you. I don't know if it's getting awkward for you. All right. Okay, so what would you like to do next? You clearly do not have the right key. The only person who may know where the key is is Kalan.
Ben Pfaff: Oh, uh, was Bookworm wearing the key?
Kostadis Roussos: Um, no.
Daz: Fuckin' key, right?
Joe Beda: Well, no.
Kostadis Roussos: Nope.
Joe Beda: We thought we had a key, but it wasn't the key, and then the other key we thought was stolen out of the locket, and we don't know where it was, and then there's the gem. Do we have the gem?
Kostadis Roussos: No, you don't have the gemline there.
Joe Beda: So we got bupkis.
Ben Pfaff: Like, I, I...
Kostadis Roussos: Well, no, but you know something important here, right? You know that the only person that went to Genussi's room between midnight, but the first person to go to Genussi's room was Bookworm, and she cut out his heart, and she knew about the key.
Joe Beda: So it's likely she had the key, and that was the reason why she was murdered.
Kostadis Roussos: Right, which would be consistent with the attempt to kill Daz.
Joe Beda: Yeah, with the, uh, with the attack of the, all right, so these, these, what are they, Helmed Horrors or whatever that attacked us?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Joe Beda: Would they kill by tearing somebody's throat out, or was it sort of a different type of enemy that would do that?
Kostadis Roussos: This is more of a claws, teeth, kind of...
Joe Beda: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Beast, Beast
Joe Beda: Thank you for watching!
Ben Pfaff: So these, these attacks seem quite different, like this is tearing out a throat and the other one was more of a magical or surgical removal of a heart. Did I say something silly?
Kostadis Roussos: All right, so, okay, okay. So, I just wanted to say something. Yes, what did you say? Sorry.
Ben Pfaff: So are the styles of these murders different?
Kostadis Roussos: Oh yes, there's very different.
Ben Pfaff: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Um, you do know, but as you're looking at that, Thorin remembers that Sylvira has an abyss-born abysmal spawn.
Joe Beda: I do? I remember.
Kostadis Roussos: Apparently, yes, you do remember that. No, actually, you don't remember that. Thorin remembers that. Daz remembers that.
Joe Beda: Oh, Daz remembers it, okay. So, who does...
Kostadis Roussos: Dad, Sylvira has an abyss-born, abyssal spawn of a son that she keeps him locked in a magical sanctuary to protect him.
Daz: Okay.
Joe Beda: Wait, wait, this is her son?
Kostadis Roussos: Well, you know, she's a tiefling, she got pregnant, it was in the abyss, bad things happen.
Joe Beda: Things happen. Okay, okay. All right.
Kostadis Roussos: What?
Joe Beda: I'm just saying, don't like, you know, don't, you know, I don't judge other cultural norms.
Kostadis Roussos: Did Brogge double Tiefling?
Joe Beda: Okay.
Daz: Interesting.
Kostadis Roussos: So, right, and so you now connect that dot, that abyssal spawn, you know, you know, the madness of the abyss, that might be a connection.
Joe Beda: Wait, what was the Madness of the Abyss?
Kostadis Roussos: Well, the madness that you guys have been dealing with, all the demon spawns.
Joe Beda: Okay. Oh, okay. So the idea there is then that maybe her son was not himself because of the whole sort of madness of the abyss and then acted. But like, what would be the motive behind that besides like demons be crazy?
Kostadis Roussos: Um, well, what you do know is that Alei Avonmore is really interested in collecting the keys, and the most useful thing to collect the keys is to open the Hightower, and the most useful thing to open the Hightower is to get some magical artifact of ineffable power.
Joe Beda: Okay, so that's the key to unlocking the gates to hell.
Ben Pfaff: Now, do they have, like, guards on this tower or anything, or just a key?
Kostadis Roussos: That's a great question. It seems like putting up. So Daryl explains, look, here's the deal. You have to understand. We have got the finest defensive mechanisms in the realms.
Ben Pfaff: You rely on magical stuff, don't you? You don't have any actual guards.
Kostadis Roussos: We have excellent guards, but our primary defense is a shield that protects anybody from teleporting in or out.
Daz: Oh
Ben Pfaff: We've got, we've got
Daz: Are we sure the teleport protection is working? Something feels off to me.
Kostadis Roussos: Um, I, I, uh... Do you have, like, a line?
Ben Pfaff: Alarms? Like, if somebody had teleported in? I mean, you told me they can't, but if someone had, would you find out?
Kostadis Roussos: And that's inconceivable!
Ben Pfaff: You know, many of us have worked in some form of information security and where, you know, inconceivable things happen multiple times a day. So, could you check?
Kostadis Roussos: He goes, he goes, well, it's very easy. You can't light, you can't, fire doesn't work in Candlekeep. You must have noticed this.
Ben Pfaff: I haven't tried to light any fires.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, try to light one!
Ben Pfaff: Okay, I try one of my basic spells. What do I have? Okay, Thaumaturgy, Fireplay.
Kostadis Roussos: Let me just see what happens in a second.
Ben Pfaff: I'm sorry, I didn't catch that.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, one more. Okay, so Daryl says, well, so you try to light the fire, nothing happens, right? Your spell sort of erupts, but then as it falls on the, as you try to cause the fire on a piece of paper so that it's not just magical, it sort of evaporates instantaneously.
Daz: Hmm.
Kostadis Roussos: Burning Bush kind of situation, right?
Ben Pfaff: Huh, I wasn't expecting that.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, okay.
Ben Pfaff: Okay, so, but what does that have to do with getting in or out of the tower?
Kostadis Roussos: It's the same magical effect. It's protected in the High Tower.
Daz: It's protected by the Hightower?
Kostadis Roussos: Well, it's in, he suddenly connects the dots in his head. It's in the room that is protected by the two keys.
Joe Beda: Wait, what's in the room that's protected by the two keys?
Kostadis Roussos: The ward that protects Candlekeep from outsiders coming in.
Daz: is in the room with the two keys.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, so just to...
Joe Beda: I mean, how do we know if that ward is still valid, right? Is there some way for us to test it?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, he just told you, you can't start fires.
Joe Beda: Oh, okay, so that's the same ward?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, yes, yes. It's a save word. Save word.
Joe Beda: Okay, so the ward has not fallen yet.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, but there's two keys and they have the whoever has the first key.
Joe Beda: Well, and we don't know where the second key is either, so it's like we're kind of like down, like we're 0 for 2.
Kostadis Roussos: but but but you but you do know somebody who does know who must know where the second key is Kalan Kalan had the original first key Kalan Strongbranch had one of the two keys
Ben Pfaff: And still should.
Kostadis Roussos: Or maybe he gave it to somebody else.
Ben Pfaff: Really, they should just not, they shouldn't just
Joe Beda: Alright, so let's
Ben Pfaff: It's shut around all the time.
Joe Beda: Clearly
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, I'm...
Joe Beda: Go interview him and or protect him and or see if he's already dead.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, I think that is a fantastic stratagem. Okay, the next question is where? Daz, why don't you roll an investigation?
Daz: All right, investigation, here it comes.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Daz: 16
Kostadis Roussos: All right. Gaz, you remember that he said, if I don't see you tomorrow, do not look for me at my post. He's not in the gatehouse. You turn to Fembris, I presume, or Daryl, and Daryl says the most likely place for him to be is in the Sea Warden's Tower, lost among the other watchers.
Kostadis Roussos: Rather than in the gatehouse, hanging out, he's probably hanging out with the troops, trying to rally them and having a beers and alcohol as he celebrates.
Ben Pfaff: There's troops here? I thought we were in some sort of like academic tower or something.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, there, there, there, there's some.
Ben Pfaff: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: We have some. We are not completely defenseless.
Ben Pfaff: Well, you have plenty of magic, but I guess swords still have their place, huh?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, we have some swordsmen. It's always important to have one. All right. Okay. So, do you want to head off to the Sea Warden's Tower?
Daz: Hmm. Yeah, I think so. Like, that might be where the room that needs the two keys.
Kostadis Roussos: Who Knows?
Ben Pfaff: I still have the fake key, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, so you have the fake key, so let me just remind you, let's help, let me just, Bookworm had a key, it was stolen by some sociopathic creature.
Ben Pfaff: Yup.
Kostadis Roussos: You're just assuming that-
Joe Beda: Anybody that would tear out somebody's throat is sociopathic. They may be well-adjusted with good methods and claws. I'm just saying.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah.
Joe Beda: Weird Methods and Clause Okay, anyway, so yes It's a murderous, murderous character, yeah
Kostadis Roussos: Fair, fair. It's hard for you to suspect that it's an isolated incident, given that somebody summoned...
Joe Beda: Clearly, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Summon creatures to attack Daz to seize the key. So the last possible place for the key is, Kalan may know where the last key is. All right. So off to the sea.
Ben Pfaff: Ordon's Tower.
Kostadis Roussos: Sea Warden's Tower Alright Alright, he goes, alright so let me just show you
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so, let me just show you where you are on the map.
Joe Beda: Ooh, it's fuzzy. Oh, there it comes. Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Sorry, it's a very high-resolution image, and, you know, the GPU and the whatnot, and the whole...
Joe Beda: Blah Blah Blah
Kostadis Roussos: and the technology and the...
Joe Beda: I blame AI.
Kostadis Roussos: Good morning, ma'am.
Ben Pfaff: Oh, there it goes.
Kostadis Roussos: I always blame Ali. Alright, so...
Ben Pfaff: I'm starting to believe that in this realm that we're playing in, magic is the equivalent of AI.
Kostadis Roussos: It is, actually.
Ben Pfaff: Okay, which number are we?
Kostadis Roussos: You guys are in 10, which is the great library. Sorry, you guys are in the great library.
Ben Pfaff: Uh oh.
Kostadis Roussos: Mithral Hall, Bahamutian School, Selûne, Plinki
Ben Pfaff: That's where we're starting.
Kostadis Roussos: just actually starting in the exaltations and so what happens is you need to run to the
Joe Beda: Whoa, what happened there?
Ben Pfaff: We got stretched. That must be magic.
Joe Beda: That's fascinating. I love it. Okay. That means we're moving really fast.
Kostadis Roussos: yes you are you have to run to the sea wardens which they didn't which is annoying that's okay we'll just declare the sea wardens over here so you have to run over here to the sea wardens area All right.
Kostadis Roussos: Where you discover that Kalan is looking very frantic. He goes, as he sees you arrive, he says, as you're heading towards him, he's heading towards you. He's kind of belting himself up, putting on his armor, rushing towards you. He goes, Grygum, Daz, I heard the bell. Is everything okay?
Ben Pfaff: Uh, no, Bookworm is dead.
Kostadis Roussos: Bookworm is dead, he pauses. Does she have the key?
Daz: We did not, um, see the key.
Joe Beda: Wait, did we investigate Bookworm's site of death and see the body and all that?
Kostadis Roussos: Well, that's it. Yes, you did.
Ben Pfaff: Yeah, we did.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, you did, yes you did.
Joe Beda: We can't say with confidence that we couldn't find the key.
Ben Pfaff: Oh, we did not find a key.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, he turns and says,
Ben Pfaff: He is gone.
Kostadis Roussos: The key is gone. He goes, well, that's fortunate. They only have one of the two keys. Right? It was an accident. It had nothing to do with the keys, right? It was just a maddening attack by Sylvira's son. I told her that that, I told Bookworm that that creature would be the death of us. You tell him the fact that you got attacked to seize the key or not.
Daz: I think we tell him and see what his further reaction is.
Joe Beda: I mean, there were enough other witnesses, he'll find out. But also, I think we ought to defend, like, look, you know, there's a lot of sort of the, you know, case of the crazies going on because of the demons and all that. So I wouldn't jump to conclusions and blame the poor kid. But, you know, I don't know. How old is the kid? Like 300 years old or something?
Kostadis Roussos: I don't know.
Joe Beda: All right, what else?
Kostadis Roussos: All right. Okay. So, Kalan looks at you. Here's about how you were attacked by creatures. He goes, you got Zooks. Someone is definitely after the keys. And he says,
Joe Beda: Does he literally say Ged Zooks?
Kostadis Roussos: I mean, sorry, he says it in...
Joe Beda: What is the, uh, what is the, okay, yeah, I'm sorry, go ahead. So, okay, he, he...
Kostadis Roussos: No, he, he, he said
Joe Beda: Surprise!
Kostadis Roussos: You know, he establishes a surprise. He goes, This is an important, urgent matter. He looks at the four of you and says, You are adventurers.
Ben Pfaff: Aye, aye.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, I hereby command you, or rather, I hereby deputize you as watchers of Kettlekeep.
Daz: What does that mean? Does that give us any privileges and or change our ability to do the investigation?
Ben Pfaff: So far we've done badly.
Daz: Does it come with a stipend?
Kostadis Roussos: A small honorarium, Daz, a small honorarium, but this is not the boy's, he goes, it's truly an honorarium, I can't promise you you'll be, why are we discussing honorariums with bookworm dead, someone out to capture the monster, and the second key, at risk?
Kostadis Roussos: He then, he looks at you, he goes, Taldrik has the key.
Ben Pfaff: Caldron
Kostadis Roussos: Uh, Todrick, he's the guy who you guys met at the Janussi's, uh, graveyard, at Janussi's, uh, room. He was the gun guarding the room from people coming in and out.
Ben Pfaff: Okay, I'm confused now about who thinks where all the keys are because don't people think that one of them was given to us?
Daz: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Kalan. Kalan was the one who gave you the fake key.
Daz: Okay.
Joe Beda: Wait, wait, so how did we get the key in the first place? I'm trying to remember.
Kostadis Roussos: Kalan gave the key to Grygumite.
Ben Pfaff: Right.
Daz: Right? And then he gave it to me, and then we realized that it's fake.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Ben Pfaff: Okay, Alan
Kostadis Roussos: And I had set you guys up to be a target.
Joe Beda: That pastored, but we could handle it.
Kostadis Roussos: Right. So he'd set you guys up to be a target. That's what you've now figured out.
Joe Beda: So Kalan was one who actually was supposed to keep the key, and he gave it to us, but he actually gave us a fake one, and he supposedly kept the original, but then he handed the original to his buddy, right, or his assistant.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, yes.
Joe Beda: What was the assistant's name?
Kostadis Roussos: Tadryk
Joe Beda: Cadric. Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Whom you met at Janussi's early in this adventure. He was the guy guarding Janussi's murder scene.
Joe Beda: Okay, so why, okay, so if, I'm just trying to think, like, so somebody sent the dudes after us to try and recover the key.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Joe Beda: And they had the information that could only, as far as we know, be given by the dude who was hanging out with us, right? Yes. And the dude that was hanging out with us was buddy-buddy with the woman who was murdered. But then she was murdered because she had the key. So that suggests that she was the one who sent the people after us to get the key.
Joe Beda: But in reality, somebody else thought that she had the key, and she may or may not have had the key, or maybe she got the key someplace else. So I'm just wondering, like, like the people who, like, who's, like, there was one key to be had, and there were two attacks. It probably was.
Kostadis Roussos: Goodbarrel, Mithral Hall, Selûne, Plinki
Joe Beda: What's that?
Kostadis Roussos: There are two keys to be had. One was on Bookworm, and the other is Kalan's other key.
Joe Beda: Oh, I see, I see, I see, I see. So, like, maybe she sent, or like, somebody sent baddies after both us and then looking to have the keys, but like, in our case they were mistaken, in the case of Bookworm they weren't.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Joe Beda: And so they have one of the keys from Bookworm, the other one, if they had succeeded against us, they thought they would have had both the keys, but they really wouldn't have because Kalan pulled an old switcheroo and didn't give us the key, gave us a Faco key.
Ben Pfaff: Did... but we just...
Joe Beda: So he could have done something to, like, imbue some magic on that key so that it glowed with the tech magic, because the tech magic doesn't tell you what the magic is, it's just there's some magic there, and then it would have been a lot harder for us to figure this shit out, but okay.
Ben Pfaff: I mean, does Kalan know that we know that it was fake?
Kostadis Roussos: He doesn't, at this point in time, he doesn't care. He's basically telling you the real keys held by Tadric.
Ben Pfaff: Okay, he's basically admitting he gave us a fake.
Joe Beda: Kalan did that because he was being screwed over and passed over and he was pissed that like he's like, like cold day in hell before I'll help these interlopers type thing, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Joe Beda: Okay. Alright, so we should definitely go get the key from Tadric, because we're probably better at holding the key than he is, because, like, you know, we got, like, swords and shit. We don't have a bowl cut haircut. What? Which is clearly...
Kostadis Roussos: Thank you for watching!
Joe Beda: Disqualifying for all the night.
Daz: That's not required, right, for this new role we're in?
Joe Beda: I don't know, I'm just, I'm reading the notes and it just says short human young bowl cut is, you know, his role, according to the notes. His role is bowl cut.
Ben Pfaff: My job is beach.
Joe Beda: Exactly, his job is bowl cut.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Joe Beda: All right, so do we know, okay, do we think it was the same people? It was probably the same person that actually went after both of us.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Joe Beda: Which may mean that, what's-his-face, who's the dude, that Fembris, who was hanging out with us? We definitely need to put the screws to Fembris and say, who do you report this to? Because it probably wasn't Bookworm, because Bookworm was murdered. It was probably somebody else who then, like, came after Bookworm and us at the same time.
Kostadis Roussos: And he pauses at that point in time and admits that when he told Bookward the information, Alay Ivanmore was in the womb.
Joe Beda: Okay, so Fembra said that. Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, yes, after you put the screws on him.
Joe Beda: Okay, so now, okay, so number one, we say, hey, Fembris, this whole idea that Tadric has the other key, don't fucking tell anybody, you asshole, right? Okay, so we tell them that. Lucillip Sinkships, dumbass.
Joe Beda: And then, and then, like, we definitely, like, I think we should probably get the key from Tadrick and then go after, who was it? It was L.A.?
Kostadis Roussos: Alley, Avonmoor
Joe Beda: Who clearly was part of the murder on the Oregon Express that helped kill everybody. Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, he's the man, he's the man.
Joe Beda: brains for the whole thing right so now this is a second piece of data against ally that like hey look ally had knowledge that nobody else had you know and it clearly you know wasn't bookworm that you know started this whole thing because like it was the same you know likely the same person trying to recover both keys so that's the second piece of information against ally okay
Ben Pfaff: I mean, there's other theories you could come up with, but that seems like a good start for sure.
Kostadis Roussos: So Kalan is very impressed with you. It says, Well done! You have captured two of the pillars of the thrice-fold proof.
Joe Beda: You're making it sound harder than it is. I mean, why don't we just say three strikes, you're out.
Kostadis Roussos: Pauses. Three slashes, perhaps?
Joe Beda: uh obviously you're not a baseball player all right
Ben Pfaff: Let's continue.
Kostadis Roussos: I'm straight
Daz: You're not a golfer.
Kostadis Roussos: No, dude!
Ben Pfaff: Three strikes and you've got at least a lot of points in bowling.
Joe Beda: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Ben Pfaff: Special thanks to our Patrons, especially to our Patrons, who have supported us through the years.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, right.
Ben Pfaff: See you right in a row.
Joe Beda: Yeah, it's called a turkey.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Ben Pfaff: You, you know, you know, uh, uh, Paul, I don't.
Joe Beda: Did you know I was at my high school's last weekend and they pulled out the old yearbook and I forgot that I was in the picture for the girls' bowling team? I was the girls' bowling team manager.
Ben Pfaff: Nice.
Joe Beda: Because all my friends were on the girls' bowling team, and so, yeah, you know.
Ben Pfaff: Yeah, that must have been nice.
Joe Beda: Yeah, all right.
Ben Pfaff: I, on the other hand, was merely the yearbook editor, so.
Joe Beda: Oh, and the yearbook had several pages going, these pages blank because the students responsible did not follow through with their commitments. It was like, fine.
Ben Pfaff: Really?
Joe Beda: It was amazing. Oh, God.
Ben Pfaff: Goodbarrel.
Kostadis Roussos: Are you serious?
Joe Beda: Oh yeah!
Kostadis Roussos: No, I mean, like, I mean, it's one thing.
Joe Beda: Like, Savage Callout, they should have named the students because that would have been better like 30 years later.
Daz: Yeah.
Ben Pfaff: Wow!
Joe Beda: Savage.
Kostadis Roussos: All right. Okay. So, I don't have this room here, but we'll just use, we'll just declare. All right. So, what he tells you is you are, he's on, what does he say? Where is he? So, hold on. It's right here.
Kostadis Roussos: He goes, he goes, Tadric, he's a loyal, and he's alone, and he does not know what he carries or what's coming for it. The Echoing Hall, then the North Galleries, I posted him away from the barracks on purpose. Run! He hands you a shortcut, a watcher's stare, key to the barred North Gallery door.
Kostadis Roussos: And it sort of cuts, it gives you a shortcut to the to the to the hall. Do you take it or?
Joe Beda: And we say, sure, and I'm like, is this key for real this time, or are you just fucking with us again?
Kostadis Roussos: He pauses, he goes, On my honor.
Joe Beda: And the other one wasn't?
Ben Pfaff: Ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha!
Joe Beda: Okay, wait, never mind, never mind, let's go, we run, okay, we can argue about this later.
Kostadis Roussos: You know, he goes, he's like running, he's trying to catch up with you, he's a little bit out of shape, a little bit on the older side as you're running.
Joe Beda: Little Rotund
Kostadis Roussos: And the writing says, ah, just for the record, I figured that if they saw you with the key, it would be fake, the fake key would be safer. I couldn't trust you with the key of that board that's...
Joe Beda: All right. Yeah. It's like, have you seen our weapons? Like, Dawnbringer here can take anybody on.
Kostadis Roussos: That's why he gave you the fake key, because he wanted...
Joe Beda: Alright, alright. We can argue about this later.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, he's trying really hard and he just sort of like stops right here like us.
Joe Beda: Carry on!
Daz: A little out of breath.
Kostadis Roussos: Goodbarrel. What?
Daz: He's a little out of breath.
Kostadis Roussos: oh yeah he's a little bit out of breath all right so you arrive on it's a dome rotunda all right you arrive at the top of the dome rotunda so let's just draw a circular room
Joe Beda: Oh, are we going to do the type of thing where we overhear somebody because there's reflecting sounds in the rotunda? Because have you ever been in one of the rotundas where you stand in the right place and then there's another place and you hear exactly the sound from the other place because it gets reflected off?
Kostadis Roussos: Would you like that? That would be fun.
Joe Beda: Okay, if you could write that in, that'd be cool.
Ben Pfaff: All right.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, it's in. It's officially in. Let's tell you what the situation is.
Kostadis Roussos: So this is what the rotunda looks like.
Joe Beda: What's-his-face that couldn't keep up with us as we were running? Kalan?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, maybe? Alright, here, let me just... Let me just, uh... Alright. Let's see here...
Ben Pfaff: I like the idea of having something special on a rotunda. That sounds like fun.
Kostadis Roussos: All right. Need to just get the right monster for this.
Joe Beda: Wait, did my sound stop working?
Daz: Okay, I'm just gonna...
Ben Pfaff: Hey, I also can't hear Custodus.
Daz: Oh, hold on. He must have lost his microphone.
Joe Beda: I just thought that something happened to me and you guys were all talking with each other and I'm like, well,
Daz: I thought Kassadis was thinking about something and looking something up, so he needed a minute.
Joe Beda: You can take a minute if he needs it, that's okay.
Daz: Yeah. Nope, nope, nope. Can't hear you.
Joe Beda: We don't, like, clearly we're not in a hurry to finish this game.
Daz: No. We will call out to you when we can hear you.
Joe Beda: Yeah, you will get some sort of sign of jubilation, positive reinforcement, virtual pats on the back. Sorry, I'm kind of exhausted. I was in Chicago last weekend with my family.
Joe Beda: And my sister is an extrovert, and is the type of person who just, like, plans everything. So, like, we had one day on Sunday where we did an architectural boat tour of Chicago in the morning, which was amazing, by the way. If you ever get a chance to go, it was totally worth it. And then we went to a Cubs game, and then we went to the airport for our...
Kostadis Roussos: Hello?
Daz: We hear you now.
Ben Pfaff: Let's go Stardust!
Kostadis Roussos: Yay! All right.
Joe Beda: And then get home until like, I don't know, 12.30, 1 a.m. like Seattle time. So, and then I have 7 a.m. meeting this morning.
Kostadis Roussos: The creature has, while you guys were running around, the creature has jumped onto Tadric, he's grappled him, and he's torn him, he's tearing him apart.
Joe Beda: Alright, so we gotta save him and his bowl cut. The bowl cut may not survive.
Kostadis Roussos: Right. Yes.
Joe Beda: All right.
Ben Pfaff: So if we have to prioritize the man or the bowl cut, we're going to have to make a choice.
Joe Beda: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, hold on. Let me just remove all turns. Okay, could you guys roll initiative?
Joe Beda: Well, it turns out the bowl cut actually gives some special powers.
Daz: Initiative 7. That's not great.
Joe Beda: Oh, I got 19. I rolled a natural 20. What the fuck? Didn't I have something that, like, I had some sort of new thing that was, like...
Kostadis Roussos: Hello.
Daz: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: I was just testing my own
Ben Pfaff: I'm here, I'm here.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, okay, so I'm just getting, I'm getting onto Zaltir's character sheet.
Joe Beda: Have we slept since the last action, because I'm wondering...
Kostadis Roussos: No, no.
Joe Beda: Okay. I'm still down to superior. I'm good. Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: There has been no, um...
Joe Beda: No rest for the weary.
Kostadis Roussos: West for the Weary. All right. Zaltir's, Moshiv, is a 16. All right. Did you guys already add your initiatives? Is that what I'm seeing?
Joe Beda: Apparently I'm, I'm, I'm winning.
Daz: Mine is in there.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Joe Beda: All right, and then the NPCs and mobs need the Pit Fiend and Tadric both need.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, Tedrick is, uh, is incapable of doing anything.
Joe Beda: So kind of smooth.
Kostadis Roussos: Mithral Hall, Bahamutian School, Selûne, Plinki
Joe Beda: Full Cut
Kostadis Roussos: Beans
Joe Beda: I mean, the word moot just has bowl-cut vibes about it, you know what I'm saying?
Kostadis Roussos: What did you say?
Joe Beda: The word moot has bowl-cut vibes about it. I don't know, somehow, it just, that makes sense to me. It doesn't have to make sense to anybody else.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, um, all right, um, okay, let's, let's, let's, I'm sure, let's see,
Kostadis Roussos: by the way when you when you see the the creature it's like this massive powerful creature that looks not particularly friendly kind of thing okay seven it's got should have been seven
Kostadis Roussos: Ozi, Kodl, Seven All right, Thorin, you're up.
Joe Beda: All right. Well, I'm definitely going to tank this shit.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, you're going to charge right at him.
Joe Beda: I mean, okay, so, number one, what do we know about this dude? Do we know anything? Can I do that without wasting an action?
Kostadis Roussos: um well you know he's a demon you know he's abyssal he's a demon spawn you know he probably has the same sets of resistances that all demon spawns have
Joe Beda: So Dawnbringer's fire is not going to do any good up against him, right? Because he's, you know, Hellspawn.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, she doesn't have, she's actually got, it actually might do because she's, she doesn't, it's not actually fire, it's radiant damage.
Joe Beda: Oh, that's right. Okay, so we'll do that.
Kostadis Roussos: Just for the record, she's upset that you didn't know this.
Joe Beda: I'm sorry, I was fooled for a second because you are a flaming sword, but you're right.
Kostadis Roussos: Flaming, flaming, flaming
Joe Beda: You are Radiant Sword!
Kostadis Roussos: Thank you.
Joe Beda: Absolutely stunning. Beautiful.
Kostadis Roussos: Daryl, Daryl sees it.
Joe Beda: Well, Daryl...
Kostadis Roussos: I still
Joe Beda: To fun places, just to be clear.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, don't you guys
Joe Beda: Let's cover this in therapy.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, we're going to have to cover this. We're going to have to have a long therapy session about it.
Joe Beda: I know, right?
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Joe Beda: So I'm, I'm, you know
Kostadis Roussos: We know the monster's kind of like going, I'm about to rip this creature's head and steal the artifact. Could we like get back to this?
Joe Beda: All right, so we're doing the whole guardian thing, so that way if the monster attacks anybody but me, I get an opportunity to attack, so that's why I'm closing here.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Joe Beda: And then my attack with Dawnbringer here. I don't think I have any excuse for advantage, so I'm just going to attack here. You know, every time we play, it's a different display here.
Daz: I know, I agree with you. They keep changing the interface.
Kostadis Roussos: They keep doing what?
Joe Beda: It's not undead, so I think we're talking total one-handed damage is 19, wait, no, because it's not undead, so it's got to be 11 is the damage.
Kostadis Roussos: In London? Yeah. Alright. And then I'm gonna
Joe Beda: Attack again. Alright, and this time, um, the damage is 12.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Joe Beda: And then, have I hurt this creature at all?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, yes, you have.
Joe Beda: Are they feeling it?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, they are.
Joe Beda: All right, so I'm going to do, let's see, I get one action surge per short rest, so I'm going to do that, and I'm going to hit them again, and this time it's eight points of damage.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Joe Beda: um so yeah that's that's some damage there and because of this let's see okay and then this is sap and so what does sap do again uh they get disadvantage on their next roll
Joe Beda: And they can't hit anybody else but me without me getting an opportunity attack.
Daz: Nice.
Joe Beda: What did you say, Castanhas?
Kostadis Roussos: No, I'm just wondering myself. Nice. All right. So, all right. All right. All right. Cool. All right. Zaltir.
Daz: Thank you for watching!
Kostadis Roussos: All right. Zaltir charges at him. He's going to go all in. Let's see if I can do this. All right.
Joe Beda: Oh wait, can I do some more before I finish?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes!
Joe Beda: I want to do a hill strike, which is an extra 1d6.
Kostadis Roussos: Peace
Joe Beda: So that's an extra four points, but it has to succeed on a strength saving throw DC 15 or have prone, so I might not get prone.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, so what is the DC trick?
Joe Beda: DC-15 Strength
Kostadis Roussos: Ah, he made it.
Joe Beda: Damn it. Okay, wait, let's see what else I can do. What else can I throw at him?
Kostadis Roussos: Keep doing that because I'm like trying to figure out what I can do here.
Joe Beda: All right, you do you.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, I'm going to do me. Okay. All right, so the first thing...
Joe Beda: Okay, so I can do...
Kostadis Roussos: Let's get some system.
Joe Beda: Oh, okay, so, um, is it worth trying to frighten him? I don't think so. He's not going to retreat.
Ben Pfaff: I don't think you can frighten a pit fiend.
Joe Beda: I could. Do you want to see me try?
Ben Pfaff: I'd love to see you try.
Joe Beda: All right, we're doing, I'm gonna, all right, where did that go? That was Menacing Attack on, okay, so Menacing Attack Strength, he has to beat a DC 15 Wisdom Saving Throw or be frightened.
Kostadis Roussos: BC 15, wisdom saving girl. Okay, you know what the frightened effect has, right? It can't attack you, or it can't advance towards you or attack you. Just keep that in mind.
Joe Beda: Right, which means I'm guaranteed to actually get a...
Kostadis Roussos: What was that?
Joe Beda: So 15, and he rolled a 13.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, he rolled a 13.
Joe Beda: Okay, so he's now frightened towards me, which means that I'm going to get the opportunity attack.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, a few moves. All right, Zaltir attacks. Okay, Zaltir, let's see what Zaltir, okay, Zaltir will attack with his Enhanced Unarmed Strike. All right, you all have Magical Item. Okay, so, let's see, where's the attack?
Joe Beda: Oh, wait, I also get an extra 1d8 on that one. Give me a second here. So that's an extra two points of damage on him, too.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, okay, okay, so, uh, did Zaltir just attack? Okay, so he takes 14, Zaltir advances on him, sent it back, right, Zaltir advances on him and attacks him once for 14 points of damage.
Kostadis Roussos: Axe again for 10 points of damage and we'll use one of his key points to try to stun him and the creature is stunned
Daz: Nice.
Joe Beda: Even better than frightened.
Kostadis Roussos: That's his friend, I'm frightened and stunned. All right, so turn on fail, save the target, and it's okay. So stunned until he is stunned, let me just make him leave that. All right, he is stunned, and it is out there. Okay, it's gonna burn.
Kostadis Roussos: So I'm going to then use my, let me just make sure that the stunning doesn't consume a bonus action.
Kostadis Roussos: Focus points. All right, and then I will expend another bonus point to attack him again. Twice to attack him twice again while he is stunned.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, takes another 30 points of damage. All right, Grygum, you're up.
Ben Pfaff: Hooray! So, we only have the one creature there, right? The pet feed?
Joe Beda: His name apparently is Mosquito.
Ben Pfaff: Mosquito the Pit Fiend. Okay. Well, so I'm going to move so other people will be out of the blast area. And then I'm really excited about this Javelin of Lightning. So I'm going to hurl it at the Pit Fiend, attempting not to hit any of my compatriots here.
Ben Pfaff: So, uh, that, uh, missed. Fuck.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, Daz, you're up.
Daz: Alright, I am, so I'm guessing a pit fiend is probably immune to, like, fire damage.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Daz: Okay, so I instead, what about, that's also fire damage.
Daz: I think I'm going to go with a good old-fashioned magic missile since he's not doing great and hold on for next round if I need anything else. So here's my magic missile.
Daz: So that is four times, what am I at now?
Kostadis Roussos: What did you do?
Daz: Uh, Magic Missile
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Daz: At the first level, so let's just say it was...
Kostadis Roussos: Well, it's a great...
Daz: Three.
Kostadis Roussos: All points of damage. All right.
Daz: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, Thorin.
Joe Beda: I get to attack again?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, you do, because Mosquito is, he is unconscious, he is stunned, thanks to Daz.
Joe Beda: His name is Mosicoto? I just read that as Mosquito.
Ben Pfaff: He's not just stunned, he's stunning.
Joe Beda: All right, here we go.
Daz: Something's wrong with my character sheet.
Joe Beda: All right, that's 11 points.
Kostadis Roussos: 11 points.
Joe Beda: Yeah, let's do that again. Oh, I don't know. Okay, so this is a critical.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, my God.
Joe Beda: I'm trying to figure out what all the
Kostadis Roussos: You killed him. You killed him.
Joe Beda: All right, so he dead?
Daz: Here we go.
Ben Pfaff: Really?
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Ben Pfaff: I expected this guy to be a lot tougher.
Kostadis Roussos: I wasn't expecting you guys to, like, win all of your initiatives and for Zaltir to knock him unconscious.
Joe Beda: I mean, even so, he would have gotten like one attack.
Kostadis Roussos: We only needed one.
Joe Beda: Really? And he could have killed the dude?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, he only needed one.
Joe Beda: And we just totally, like, one-shot him.
Ben Pfaff: Oh, we ished him.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, I just want to say, like, well done.
Joe Beda: So my going hard on them was worth it, okay, on the first round there.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, yes, like the going all out was the right strategy. I thought I...
Ben Pfaff: Let's get at least another attack, wow.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, no, I mean, I have to say, well done. You, like, all sort of ganged up on him and knocked him out. But you still have a problem. You have Alai Evanmore, who's got one of the two keys.
Joe Beda: Okay, so the plan was that we were going to like, so the plan was that we were going to kill him, but first he was going to kill the dude with the bolt cut.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, to go to the Hightower. So you now know probably where he is. He's probably in the Hightower.
Joe Beda: Yeah, and so saving bowl cut doesn't really get us anything except we're good people.
Kostadis Roussos: Who's the bald cat?
Joe Beda: Oh, the dude that he had, he was attacking when we showed up.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, I mean, yeah, you got to keep one of the two keys.
Joe Beda: Right, but, oh, if he had killed him, he would have actually disappeared with the key.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes!
Joe Beda: Oh, does he have some special ability to, like, just blink out of there once he sort of... It's called...
Kostadis Roussos: Disengage and flying.
Joe Beda: Okay, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Although with Zaltir in the flying potion, it was going to be kind of interesting.
Joe Beda: All right, so it was kind of dicey whether he was going to get away with the key, but you were pretty sure that bowl cut was going to die.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Joe Beda: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: No, it was no, if he killed him, he would kill him and then flee. And so my theory was he would flee, but you guys did a massive.
Joe Beda: I mean, like, not only did we keep them from fleeing, we saved Bolkut.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, you saved, you saved Boldcut. Tedrick is, I mean, Grygum, are you going to heal him or are you going to let him bleed out to death?
Ben Pfaff: I'm going to heal him, of course.
Kostadis Roussos: All right.
Ben Pfaff: I have, I'm sure I have an appropriate spell here.
Kostadis Roussos: All right. Yeah. Sure.
Ben Pfaff: Everyone's okay?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, yeah, Swine Cure Wins is efficient. He's, he's, he's...
Ben Pfaff: Cool, cool.
Kostadis Roussos: His wounds heal, the blood stops, he grabs for the key and he says, The creature, Mozikolo, he looks at him, Silvara, son, what has happened here? Do you fill him in or?
Joe Beda: I mean, he seems like he's a bit player in this drama, so I figure we might as well tell him what's going on.
Kostadis Roussos: He sits down in shock. Is Kalan alive?
Joe Beda: I mean, when we left him, but he was breathing really hard because he was running, so who knows how things ended there.
Daz: Try to have a coronary, there's no going.
Kostadis Roussos: We might have had a coronary. All right, okay, so we will stop here, you all gain a level.
Ben Pfaff: That brings us to level nine.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Daz: Yes.
Joe Beda: Thank you for signing.
Kostadis Roussos: We're now level nine.
Daz: Ah, the level, that's awesome.
Joe Beda: Burnout level without actually doing the work. Good job, Gabe.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, well, I mean, he did, you know...
Joe Beda: I'm kidding, I'm kidding.
Kostadis Roussos: So, yes. So Zaltir burned a couple of ki points, and the creature is dead. You have one of the two keys, but as you well know, evil geniuses have more than one plan.
Ben Pfaff: What fun. So we have one real key and one fake key, and anybody who doesn't know that we have a fake key, we can fake them out with it somehow.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Daz: Yes. And eventually, the person that has the real key will be like, how are these guys saying they have two keys?
Ben Pfaff: Yeah, that's a good idea. Interesting.
Daz: I'm going to ferret him out. Him or her. Or they. Or it.
Ben Pfaff: or Z
Daz: See you.
Joe Beda: So, my wife does gender-affirming care, and she'll tell me stories, and I'm down with whatever pronouns, whatever, right? The whole it thing kind of creeps me out a little bit, but whatever, you do you. But there are some people who are like, no pronouns.
Joe Beda: which is just the most awkward thing because that means that every time you refer to that person you have to actually say something like that person or use their name or whatever you can't use any pronoun when referring to
Daz: I went over to Frank's house and Frank made dinner and Frank made the Daz.
Joe Beda: Like, what the fuck, dude? Just like...
Daz: Thank you very much for taking the time out of your day to do that.
Joe Beda: Like, you're just fucking with people at that point, right?
Daz: Frank said that Frank would share Frank's record.
Joe Beda: You're pretty woke, but at that point you're just fucking with me, right?
Daz: So, um...
Ben Pfaff: We actually did that as almost like a word game in college of trying to see how long you could talk about, I think it was without using pronouns at all. A heck of a challenge.
Daz: Have you seen the caveman translator that saves tokens with your AI usage?
Joe Beda: I haven't yet, but I'm doing this whole thing where I'm like, I'm going to have a big blog post talking about how we have user experience and we have developer experience, but there's a new thing, agent experience, where it's like you optimize tools and systems to actually minimize context, window, bloat, and all that. And so the caveman is a good example of that.
Daz: Just stripping all the A's and the B's and all of the stuff that's superfluous for like actually understanding context if you're a computer.
Joe Beda: No, but I'm building this thing where I'm building this tool and I'm like, and I'm having the agent sort of have a set of scenarios and we're like looking at like, you know, the percentage usage of context and how much it saves us to use one syntax versus another and it's kind of crazy. It's kind of an interesting thing to optimize for. Like, oh, making this change saves you 1% of your context. I'm like, all right.
Daz: Eventually, there's going to be another breakthrough.
Joe Beda: Yeah. Gustavus, did we lose you? No, your audio is gone. You're silent again. Okay, you have a week to figure this out, okay?
Daz: I think he can hear us, we just can't.
Joe Beda: No, I'm pretty sure he can hear us, but we can't hear him.
Daz: Now you're back.
Joe Beda: No, you're back, you're back.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so I'm just trying to follow. So you guys, once again, twisted this adventure in new ways, so I'm going to have to go do a whole bunch of preparation.
Joe Beda: Sorry!
Daz: No, no, no!
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, this is great. This is great. I mean, you know.
Joe Beda: You have a bunch of matrices to help you, so you're good.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, there's billions of GPUs, burning cycles, helping me figure this out. I hope you guys are enjoying this. I'm enjoying this.
Joe Beda: No, we're having a...
Ben Pfaff: Oh, it's fun.
Daz: It's a ton of fun.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, so just so you know, so the key, just so we all remember on the cliffhanger, you have the key, Ale has the other key, you probably know that he's in the high tower because he was going to be waiting there for Mosley Kodo to show up with the key.
Joe Beda: Yeah.
Daz: So we show up in the Hightower, challenge, we get both keys, and then we own Candlekeep, right? That's how this works?
Kostadis Roussos: Exactly!
Joe Beda: Yeah, and then we can extract whatever boon we'd like since we deferred negotiation.
Daz: Yeah!
Joe Beda: Until later.
Daz: I just saw one of the acolytes to go fetch a scroll.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, yeah. All right. Okay, guys.
Joe Beda: All right.
Daz: All right, we'll see you guys later.